Kahin Akram

Data Scientist | Ph.D. in Data Visualization

Motivated data scientist with 6+ years of experience as an Information Visualization researcher and 1+ years of experience as consultant at own startup. Relevant skills include machine learning, problem solving, programming, and creative research thinking. Achievements include Ph.D. in abstract Information Visualization from Linköping University, data scientist at Scania Group, and leading UX/UI related projects.

EXPERIENCE

DATA SCIENTIST | SCANIA GROUP

Jan 2022 - present | Stockholm | Remote

- → Data scientist with many years of research experience providing data-driven solutions to better understand battery charging failure of Scania's new electrical vehicles. Developed an end-to-end pipeline to analyze log data with unsupervised learning techniques such as PCA, tSNE, Apriori/Eclat, and more. Derived actionable insights from the datasets with minimal support and provided refinement of existing data collections methods to improve analysis and model development.
- → Used: Python3, Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn (pipeline, unsupervised, PCA/t-SNE, Apriori/Eclat), feature-engine, Dash Plotly, and Data Storytelling.

PRODUCT OWNER | TECHFORGOOD AS (CO-OWNER)

Jan 2022 – present | Norrköping | Remote

- → Product owner with a passion for leadership assist a team of three, articulate product vision, and implement an MVP for my web2/web3 "AirbnB for computing power". Translating features into user stories within the team's backlog while managing, ranking, and prioritizing the list to reflect the requirements.
- → Used: Kanban, project management/organization, leadership, Figma, Trello, etc.

HCI ADJUNCT | THE AMERICAN UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN

Jun 2021 – dec 2021 | Norrköping | Remote

- → Course responsible who developed rigorous lesson plans, lectures and prepared students for quizzes, projects, and examination on the HCI topic.
- → **Used:** Interaction Design Beyond Human-Computer Interaction to create course content, Figma, Trello, and more as teaching tools.

PROJECT LEADER | Norrköping Science Park

Apr 2021 - Sep 2021 | Norrköping | On-site

- → Project leader who managed and mentored a team of six to prepare an application for a European Digital Innovation Hub initiative with a focus on aviation in the greater Norrköping area.
- → **Used:** Kanban Methodology, Trello, Teams, etc.

PROJECTS

PORTFOLIO BUILING ON OWN SERVER | RASPBERRY PI

Ongoing

→ I constantly seek to improve my skills and learning by exploring side projects using data technologies such as Ubuntu server, PySpark, Docker, NextCloud, and other ML-related tools and libraries.

CONTACT

- linkedin.com/in/kahinakram
- github.com/KahinAkramHassan
- ⋈ kahin.akram.hassan@gmail.com
- +46 (0)70 494 13 59

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

Data Visualization • Data Mining Machine Learning • Python • SQL

SOFT

Problem-solving • Critical Thinking • Communication • Leadership • Team Player

LIBRARIES/FRAMEWORKS

Flask • Scikit-Learn • Dash Plotly • D3.js/Chart.js

TOOLS/PLATFORMS

Git • Docker • Raspberry Pi • OS(macOS, Linux, Windows)

CREATIVE

Figma • LAT_EX• Workshop planning • Agile Dev.

LANGUAGES

Native: Kurdish •

Proficiency: English, Swedish • Hobbyist: Spanish, Arabic

EDUCATION

LINKÖPING UNIVERSITY

Ph.D. IN INFORMATION
VISUALIZATION
Jun 2016 - Mar 2021 | Sweden

LINKÖPING UNIVERSITY

B.Sc. & M.Sc. IN MEDIA TECHNOLOGY AND ENGINEERING Aug 2010 - Jun 2015 | Sweden